So, drawing levels is, I can see that you're doing it on your...
Yeah, it's just that I'm not...
The level of accuracy and everything, like, how yours are, it's just nowhere near it, really.
All right, so, in theory, this was the original pickup, yeah?
Yeah.
Can you see how price came down and grabbed the top there?
It basically fed into it, so the new area of unpick liquidity would have been there.
Okay, okay.
And then this went and grabbed the top.
it, let's say, to the halfway point.
So the new unpicked area of liquidity was this.
Now, if you look at it,
price actually came and responded.
Yeah. Now, every
pickup itself has a certain bay of liquidity
as well. So every time price grabs the
level, there'd be liquidity in there
as well. Okay. But isn't
that usually, like, weaker?
Yes. Okay.
Over time, you'll validate that it's weaker because of the types
of responses you get off here. So if you have
one level and a pickup, which
one would you use over time, you will have to try
both and at the time you'll find that it's typically the feeder the original okay now what I want
you to do is like pull up a chart like let's say this and essentially just identify where price
responded off okay you can you can see price went out and grabbed the top side on the way up
on the way down they just went to the bottom and it kind of drained that area yeah now this
picked up the bottom side so that has its own bit of liquidity on the way out price grabbed it and
run and um it basically comes down to like how you over over your experiences at the time what you'll
find is the best way to draw your levels on depending on how they look and the worst way but in essence
the unpicked part of this would have been the bottom side here and price didn't respond off
they actually responded off the pickup of the top this time yeah the price run out grab the top
there's two levels there then and they actually end up responding off the top quite uh
perfectly and then that grabbed this own liquidity as well
the top side was grabbed and this went slightly deeper into
so we can just constantly see price reaches for the part of the level that isn't picked up
yeah we had this whole level here from the top to the bottom
but on the way out price grabbed it numerous times
that would be the unpick level and price grabbed it there
this is now the unpick level and price grabbed it there washed it all out
can you see yeah that hasn't sound level there
prize didn't really even get to it so it's essentially
I'm going to set you a task to pick find a chart and identify all the points
where price responded off just so you're visually aware of the fact that there's
liquidity almost everywhere and when you're drawing your levels I want you to
obviously draw them to the part of this unpick liquidity now when you start off
on the higher time frame so if I went over 15 minutes
the level would originally start off like this because it would look like
The price has run out and picked it out one time and continued.
When you zoom into it, you find that, okay, there's numerous levels inside of the level itself.
And that's where the refining comes into place.
So we identify, let's say, a large area of liquidity.
Let's just say this one.
Yeah.
How should I draw this level originally?
Where did price pick up?
Where you've got it there right now.
All right.
But where was it picked up from this level here?
did it just move straight out
would it price come back and grab it
yeah it went out
and then it came back in
so we should refine that level to that
yeah yeah that's it already
and obviously we know the pickup itself has
liquidity there yeah yeah
the price run out likely
and came back and picked it up there and move
so now I've turned the 15 minute area
a 50 minute core into two levels
now we're going to refine it further
move down to the five
right I'd end up to find this level down
to that.
Press moved out,
came back in,
you could technically do that
because then that would
create two more levels.
They're not that far apart.
There are four pips wide.
I want you to,
I want you to pick every level.
Separate them all up.
Right?
And then in this
essentially here,
this release point is where
likely the shot of volume
came to push that candle
through to new highs.
Now if you break that area down
further you can actually see
some more granularity turn can you see now
price run out
came back grab the top and push through
so I've turned this whole 15
minute area into two
levels really
can you see it
yeah that's why your stops are usually
like very
if I just pick these two levels
I'd imagine we'd get some
responsiveness so we've spun
off the bottom one first
bear a mind doesn't mean that price will
always respond.
Yeah, of course, of course.
But that's a six-pip response,
and then this is technically invalidated it,
but 20 pips.
Yeah.
All right, so I want you to practice that.
So the way it works is go pick a random level.
You probably need J4X for this.
Go pick a random level,
draw it on, draw where the liquidity is.
So there's some there.
You see how price run out,
grab the top, and run through.
Yeah.
Technically, we could create two levels out of that.
can you see how what this is what is this picking up it's actually hitting this level here
and it went deep into it so washed it out so now I've got two levels at the core
price responds off the bottom one technically responded of the top one but it wasn't a
manageable response yeah a manageable would be a good seven eight pips that we can manage
because that response gives us a cushion of profit and then whatever happens after that
is very unlikely we'll take a full loss yeah because of the way we we essentially
manage that pickup.
We know the original pickup should hold, etc.
In this case, we got this pickup, price failed to
continue pushing higher and it ended up taking out the
original pickup. That's where our invalidation would be.
But this is essentially what I want you to practice.
Pick levels on historical charts, this is something you can do
in your downtime, in your board time.
Yeah, yeah.
Pick levels, I don't know, if I close my eyes, I go here.
Do you want to pick up like every level, like starting from the apex?
up? No, no, so
I'm saying you're like
two, essentially two tasks.
Okay.
That's a shelf, yeah?
Yeah, I don't know how to...
You draw the shelf just like you draw a level,
but you pay your no attention to where it was picked off.
You just draw the full shelf.
Okay.
So, like, technically the cell liquidity
inside of the shelf would have been here.
See, if I was to do it,
I would literally just use
like that, which
is there as you're a shelf yeah completely wrong compared to yours i'm just drawing the full shelf i
to be honest i should show you why that's the full shelf it's only visible on a 15 there uh see i would
i would do it like this that's an order block yeah see this is this is the thing that's a that's a
that's a breaker what the fuck yeah yeah um the reason a break is technically wrong is because he says
that trapped shorts here end up being long here, right?
Assuming that they're fucking people, you know, you're only a trapped short if you're
a speculative, i.e. you care about where the price goes after you took a trade.
What if they sell liquidity there is from an entity that has no interest about where the price
is going to go? They just need to transact for operational purposes.
That's the FX market.
Yeah. Then the retail traders are trapping the ozone, they apparently?
Oh, fuck you.
Bro, our volume doesn't end up in the market, man.
Yeah, yeah, I know, you said it just gets dealed off
just by our broker, doesn't it?
Internally, with the broker.
Yeah.
Now, the broker obviously builds up a risk position
that they might have to hedge out on the market,
you know, sooner or over the later,
but that's not your volume move the market,
that's the broker.
And either way, yeah?
So your shelves are the full level,
man, that's clearly the shelf.
The last inventory that pushed price to new lows.
Okay, see, see, the reason why I would say,
that here is because it paused here and then he went down yeah so on a on the fractal
price run yeah at those lows that it's a shelf so here we had a small shelf bit move up and we
broke shelf here we moved down cell base is hold cell base is hold first break of the last cell base
this pushed it to you know his first break and then pop yeah this is your your small shelf and this is
your the largest swing shelf okay yeah yeah yeah as well as obviously as i do my task um
i'll send them to you and then you can tell me if i'm like doing it right or i'll go on so
draw the unfilled liquidity of this part please okay um okay so price went up came back down's
that yeah that's lower now isn't it that's lower
it's like no that low held that low held yeah okay then it's like literally just like
that isn't it but there is no liquidity there because it's been grabbed no this was the
original level price went and grab the bottom of it you know yeah so that original level's gone
and then this so like here yeah because this was the last pickup yeah of that level
that's holding the liquidity now price run up and grabbed it and now this would then be
the level of liquidity yeah yeah yeah you could easily be mistaken and draw that whole
level but that's technically incorrect okay the level start that's that's where the
liquidity is not there yeah to get it same thing applies with this there's a small
level here price grabbed it grabbed it grabbed it is likely all grabbed so I
color coordinate what area is a liquidity gray but this one here for instance no we had one
pick up there and then price run out grabbed it again and in this instance obviously this
would be the unpick part this has a small unpick part here this area is drained and washed
we ran out came back grabbed it this one pumped through grabbed it that's unfilled
liquidity there technically you're right and saying that's unful liquidity there now do you
think oh sorry don't think that all these levels if I'm drawn them like this that they
all tradeable that's nothing we're not in that realm yet yeah just discussing with you where the
liquidity was and why price was reaching down to grab it and of course you have that level there
price ran out came and grab the top etc price responds off that we have this area this is what you
would call washed and drained because it's grabbed it grabbed it grabbed it grabbed it grabbed it grabbed it
the only area that wasn't drained was this one that shot out yeah right and then obviously we have
this small level here as well let's just draw all of them on see why go on now
you see this this particular level here yeah I would readjust it down to the
release point where the candle released out from okay right so price this
low ends up hitting right past the wash level into nothing possible no trade
there hit the first level 17-pip response slightly poked past the next level but
would have been there would be a 50-pip response
and then the last level just didn't work.
But can you see how we selected our levels
and then went to look at that
and we refined our levels,
assessed this whole area.
This is a small shelf, big shelf.
This is technically a BA, but it's washed.
This is the original pickup
and this is a fractal shelf retest
of this small one here.
Wouldn't this one not be this now?
What?
Wouldn't this level be like this?
Up there, I understand what you said.
This is where my personal preference comes in.
Technically, you're correct.
Can you see how this leg has nothing here?
Yeah, yeah.
I just did it to the release point.
Technically, you should have been there.
I didn't into the release point.
Yeah.
But yeah, the way you should draw it is like that.
Over time, you will see which types of levels work best,
how to best refine them, how far deep price went into your,
goes into your levels, et cetera, et cetera.
And as a result of that information, you will start,
you'll make small adjustments in drawing levels you'll become more
comfortable in drawing levels etc but this task of going back to a random day
selecting let's say close my eyes all right it's too easy let's take this clearly two levels
the level there small levels of equity there small levels there this would be the shelf
this would be the shelf retest pick up this would be the BA this would be
would be the top side in this instance the B is very very close to the Bacogs yeah and these
would be shifting points the small levels that push through the bids here and
pushed out okay all right we just draw I'm not drawing my lowest perfectly
but I mind then we have this pick up at the top we have all right we have this area
you can draw this as well technically is right this was a ramp on the way out
can you see what you'll come to find
is whenever you have these small
drifty type areas
they're typically going to be drained
it's not usually
there's usually not going to be a lot of saliquity
or any bi-liquity in them
because they were picked
so many times
right
in other case
you have to remember
I'm drawing like 50 10 levels here
30 level whatever it is yeah
realistically I'll draw one or two
yeah yeah because those are the only ones
that I've got out of interest to you
actually no you know
so the way it works is
I might draw all of these levels
I might be aware of all these levels
but my price came to the first one
it wasn't moving the right way
and then it moves through these
in the wrong way
so I took no trade
and then it made it through this one
it didn't move in the right way
and then finally it moves right way
did you get it
yeah yeah so like say
in the ones down here
they were moving like efficiently
through it and then
one of them went inefficient
yeah oh shit
so the first levels here that would have been an overnight high the second level actually didn't hit that so the first level's gone second level probably shot through preceding that it became very very inefficient it's that type of inefficiency can't be much room you have to remember it's still technically responding they're just not big response yeah runs through the next one and the next one hits and then runs through so this level didn't work is
well or the price starts to be efficiently to it yeah the next level also
doesn't work top side the top side doesn't work as well and price reaches to
the we looked at a higher time frame this would be the original pick-up this
would be the sh can you see now yeah all right so stay on this time frame
move out to the high time frame so stay on this view of the market you are to the
higher time frame this
was the original pickup right we were just looking at this small pickup of the OP yeah to be the
apex retest it's usually it shouldn't be basically any surprise in an apex over time what you'll find
is the original pick up the retest price feeds off this and not that yeah so it will usually reach
for that and work its way there but there's right now um we responded off past this high
We responded there, would have been like an 11-pip response.
Then it ends up, because like we said, this area, I expected to be washed, these areas here.
So it rolls over all the levels, basically, because of you shit.
It's a 40-mp response, but it rolls over all the levels,
but it gives you a response at the first, no response at the second, I think.
A response at the first, no response at the second, a response at the third,
and just to give you an idea
that's like 5-pip response
the 0.8 to stop
it's nearly 8%.
The first one would have been about
3, 4-5-pip levels, 40-pip response
so again
we're not taking all of these trades
we're not using all these levels. The point here is
that you just get used to drawing levels on
and see how Christ responds to them
and then also differentiated between levels as well
like this is the top side of the original pick-up
that's completely different to the shifting point
here that absorb the bias.
is there. Yeah, yeah.
And that's completely different to a residual. That's
completely different to an apex retest.
Yeah, so you want me to give them a location as well,
yeah? Always, always.
Give them a categorization. Okay.
And then price respond off that one,
didn't respond off that one, and respond off the top
and results in a pretty big trade.
Yeah, that's cool.
So that's the way to practice
drawing new levels. And another
way to draw your attention
visually to where price response.
It's simply having a chart like this.
and just go mental with it and berserk with right price responded off that and then it ends up going a bit deeper then price responds off the next level there and then price responds let's say off this level no actually if we look at this original level there's the pickup at the bottom it ends up responding off it and then let's say we have these levels here price responds quite invalidates it also we have the lower pick up there and it looks as if price
went straight through it we have obviously this level here price responds off it and then price
responds there responds there obviously you can zoom in icon because i'm using these squares and essentially
identify all the response points just to draw your attention to how consistently price responds off
liquidity bases and also experience the different variations of liquidity basis as well because
obviously many many different types some are closed together some liquidity bases are like this
some liquidity bases are just
drifty type liquidity
bases some are like this
yeah they leave a whole
bunch of cell liquidity there
the different variations
refining this is easy you have one
one area refining this
you have that
and that
yeah there's your show
this one is likely a residual you have that
you have that you probably have some level
there which one do you use
you need to test every single type of
equity race every many many times over so you can when you're put when you're given this situation
you know which one's the best one to use yeah when you're given this situation you know which
one's the best one to use you get it yeah yeah that's cool so that's uh one of the tasks the other
task the more important one is obviously to go back draw fucking levels refine them go have a look
of your price responded don't cheat do it over and over and over again yeah and your developmental
to task remains
now tracking it yeah
let's give you one minute
what's price doing right now
what has price just recently done
what stands out to you
extension past
the low filled
extension past the low
now maybe I want to assess why did it extend past
that low what
why was that low weak
you can clearly see
price came into buy liquidity there
came into buy liquidity there
look at the response
tries to move
fails. It actually at one point looked as if
buyers could have been strong there. Let's show you a scenario
that was possible. Sometimes it will happen. We had that shelf there
that pushed, this is the last shelf that pushed it to new lows. We went to
the top side of that shelf, came back for Apex Retest, what if this just did this?
Yeah, yeah, could have been a scenario. Easily possible.
Yeah. When you're there, you should be aware that this is a possible Apex
that's responding off by liquidity and then what subsequently happens is we have by
liquidity there fails to move price goes deeper slightly fells to move price goes deeper and you can
actually see here it didn't move straight through it it actually it actually ticked around
on the bottom side at this level it and picked it and picked it and then even here i'm quite
positive if i went to lower time frame it didn't move straight through it that the end of the
The candle ended there.
Oh yeah, I want to show you how that apex filled.
Look, we got rid of this liquidity.
That picked his own up.
We got rid of that.
That picked us own up.
Price grab and got rid of that.
Then went deeper into it.
Got rid of that.
That picked his own up.
And price went deeper.
So we just drained this area.
Move lower.
Responded slightly off the bottom side there.
With lower.
Into the next and last area of bi-liquity.
Responded slightly.
didn't even move and then pushed through.
Yeah.
You can see there was a fight going on here.
Think about it.
This picked up liquidity has its own liquidity.
Price grabbed that then and moved out of the way.
And then this grabbed its own liquidity.
Price grabbed that and then moved out of the way.
Price then went deeper because after this area was cleared,
there was lack of buy liquidity.
They had to go deeper to find it.
They did the same.
Then move lower and the bids obviously were quite in back at that point.
Yeah.
Right?
Take this low.
Grabed it.
Price ran out.
came back kind of we only respond off these these two residual areas
you know microscopically and then price comes down grabs this level
responds moves down comes to the next level inside of it responds and then essentially just
pushes people what i want you to notice is look we had a shot two candles of nothing
because there's some by liquidity supporting price and then we had another shot and it accelerates
through it yeah right it almost always does the same shit but the point here is this could have been
the apex that turns to a reversal when you were there and you know assuming you were there this would
have been your shelf this would have been your op your original pickup and you're just identifying what
price is doing rather than saying yeah price would go up or now at that junction there you're just
assessing what price is doing now so prices just come into this fractal core that's a shelf
I would class this area as all drained
because Price grabbed it, grabbed it,
and then went to the top.
Yeah.
What's the significance of it being drained?
Meaning there's lack of sell equity there.
Yeah, you shouldn't really have any problems to get through.
Yeah, just not think of it this way.
It's possible that we see weakness in sellers there
and price pushes through.
Yeah.
But lo and behold, Price had a midflow here.
I would class that as a break of midflow.
We ran, ran, ran.
held bases start to become inefficient here you can't you see it becomes inefficient runs runs
and then we have a quite a straight shot through into the shelf retest fractal quite perfectly so we
had the high broke the shelf broke the shelf retested the shelf and then broke down you could have used
this level that's not a bad level of my at all to be honest but there you had two levels there
price went to the top side
that would have been
an experience of you selecting
to having two levels
not knowing which one to use
and price gave you an answer
obviously that's not enough information
to like all the time
use the top side
are you following me
so yeah
price ran through
here's the shelf
so all I've done so far
is give price context
now I'm just going to track it
all right
here we didn't really
hit nothing
I'm fed off nothing
this run has a shelf
we just had a highly inefficient shot
let's just say
I picked up sell liquidity from the OPE
we have to remember
contextually whatever sell liquidity is here
is likely weak
so whatever you're surprised if price held
and just pushed through
but it's also possible
considering how far this is
the further runs against the weak rate gets
this is also broke midflow here
and it did become slightly inefficient there
and now we've just broke shelf
it's likely that the bids
are just strong enough
they're just not strong enough
it doesn't take much selling
to push price down
price now drawing back up
to this fractal
liquidity
sell liquidity base
let's just observe what happens
I'm literally saying
observe don't predict
price response
now I imagine that response there
imagine price goes through it
and you just looked at it
after the fact
you would never have really
visualized what that response meant
but it genuinely responded there
Yeah, it went up, it came down,
but it seems as if there's not enough sellers there
and it's likely going to push through.
When we see it after the fact,
it's not, it's hardly ever that claim,
but that literally responded off cell liquidity there.
Yeah.
And the reason it's not pushing through to new highs
is because there's still cell liquidity there
and now that volume shot pushed through.
Now this is an extension.
This is an extension past this high.
It's relatively inefficient,
coming into sell liquidity there,
but we have to remember that the sell liquidity
is coming from a weak area.
so it's possible that price yeah it responds like you just did there or it could push through
and then respond there yeah do you know what's going to happen no there's many possibilities
yes you need to experience that exact time time time again so you're confident yeah this is
going to happen more times than not this has edge this doesn't have edge just please try to think here
let me just try to write down the contextual um features that are present here yeah
so we have a washed area
cell liquidy
at the top there
yeah fractal apex
fractal
uh sorry
response on the way down
left obviously
left the fractal apex
yeah
inefficient
midflow into
fractal washed
apex
yeah
broke midflow
now what we've just
seen is one of the is the leg so here we have the original pickup this would technically be the
apex retest yeah yeah apex retest fractal price run highly efficient picked top side of you know
it's highly efficient here because look it's just stable as shit inefficient price run this
one has now broke shelf yeah opi present original pick up
So here I'm just laying out the contextual information, yeah?
How many, so here's one component.
Here's a second component.
Here's a third component.
And then here's like two or three components here.
There's five combinations of different contextual and contextual parameters, features, locations, etc.
What is the likelihood you're going to experience this exact dynamic 20 times in a row so you can make 100 times in a row so you know the exact way to trade this next time?
very unlikely basically
you are not going to be in this position
straight away next time you're
we're now completely in a different dynamic now
because price just broke this fractal run show
this fractal like there
there's a pickup at the highs obviously
and we don't know what's going to happen next
we maintain that the cell weakness there
we can see that bids are holding their prices here
holding the bases here
right and to be honest that should be
so here we have a fractal run
that's a fractal run
that has its own shelf
my original shelf was wrong
and then this is actually the big shelf
of this move here
what do we know what's going to happen
is coming in for an apex re-test
of the apex re-test
of the original pickup
it could sell off
it could move through
I maintain likely that this is washed
and we should be actually shooting through it
there's now weakness in this run
if we did shoot through it
later the day I might snap that up
and push it right back
down. But again, we're not, sorry, I shouldn't go into the territory of the realm of
forecasting, right? We're just observing what's going on. You have to remember, for me to
reach this point, I should already be aware of everything that's happened down here and I should
be tracking it chronologically. So all these levels should be drawn on already and stuff. But I just
quickly started where we are. Yeah. All right. Price is doing nothing. It's relatively inefficient
for spawning off this top side. We might need a friend of you here. All right. So how
Highly efficient.
He had this small, small shot.
The bit, there's a small shelf here.
Let's observe.
Bits holding, there's your shot.
There's that highly inefficient shot.
Coming into the washed area, liquidity, it could respond.
It definitely could respond, but it's washed.
Now, how many do you know the probability of a washed area responding?
It's low.
I don't know about the...
Have you experienced it?
No.
You're 100% right and saying low.
But until you experience it,
and say you won't know you won't believe it now what if a washed area here's a washed area
there's two washed areas there's one and there's two price is approaching this one but it's
maintaining strong midflow and it becomes inefficient into it price is approaching this one and it
broke midflow broke shelf and there's a sideways pop into it which one's more likely do you the right one
the right yeah yeah they both washed though but the contextual uh environment
it's completely different in terms of how price is moving up.
Yeah, yeah.
You're right.
Right?
So there can be times where a watch table works.
And look, I just drew that level there.
Yeah, it's just responding.
It came into it.
It's responded.
Here's your shelf.
It could ease.
We even saw this becoming inefficient.
It literally just snapped up there.
Because there was an absolute void of sell liquidity created.
Think about what happened.
The volume shot came in.
The market responds.
Cell liquidity disappears.
And the next available price.
that the buyers can buy it was here let's say and that happened again you get it yeah that
left behind and a thinn area of traded prices and traded the lack of volume trade and where does
price go right back to where the volume was and now we're just settling off into a range
i still maintain that this really is in a strong area of so liquidity uh we should at least
punch through it now let's bring in more contextual information here we have this
big shelf of this large move down this is now washed that's trained to fuck where is the left
over liquidity in that level there is some but where is it technically uh it'd be the last bit
wouldn't it yeah the last bit that yeah yeah that one yeah when it left same thing applies here
i would class this as a fuck it it's technically a area of sell liquidity i personally wouldn't
use it right but that is and can you see how this is feeding off
the top side that has its own barely could be there as well now on from the rest of your you know
from now one i want you to have your charts full of these levels when you're tracking them just like
the way i'm doing it now yeah i want your charts to be full of them if you like right now we can't
you know because it's end of days low low volume and that we can't see much so i have to look inside
of it but realistically you don't need a three-tick chart when it's 2 p.m. right you're one minutes
your five minutes use all the time frames
I hope what I'm saying makes sense
yeah yeah so obviously you're only using the tick chart now
because of uh
yeah I can't see shit
yeah yeah basically
and if you can't see shit you need to go
you need to go down to tickchats
so here's an Apex Street test
the original pickups holding those far
remember the sell liquidity feeding
that pickup is watched
got it's money man
not yours bro
all right yeah so
pickup came in
uh we hit
it multiple times all the sell liquidity in that pickups gone yeah all the sell liquidity that pickups
gone and price just pushed through it now where's the shelf technically bro that's where i'm
gonna break this fucking computer i'm spazzing out the way i'm clicking in it anyway there's a fractal
shell yeah of this run and technically this would be the big shelf if i was to show you on a five
minute there you go that would be the big show at that time there's not anymore price has shot through it
exactly like it should have you said and it's highly inefficient now the problem is there's no level of
sell liquidity there you need to practice trying to trade it is there sell liquidity let's have a
quick look can we see there can we see any there no oh shit now yet more of a granular view
there's some shitty liquidity there now that was the that's a level can you see how rice picked
picked picked picked i wouldn't be too confident that level and is technically washed there
so all we're seeing here is multiple levels that are residual and they're not too too well defined
they pick themselves up run pick themselves up picked picked and run this is technically a shifting
point and this is also a residual shifting point you can draw this if you want but can you see
price run came down and it came up cleared that area out and ran down I would be too confident
that same with this
that in my opinion is washed
and we'd be really
looking for a deep shot into it but that wouldn't
be too bad of a level as well
so it's getting interesting now
we have sorry my boxes are all over the shop
we have just broke
midflow
here's becoming super thin
just missed the level and just saw some
selling come through that's it
it clearly broke midflow twice
here's your last shelf now
I'm constantly having to update what prices
doing yeah it's moving as well we get new information all the time and we just had a very very
thin shop there into residual liquidity but the fact that it responds off residual liquidity is a kind
of confirmation of how weak this run is now is broke mid-flow here it was showing signs of you know
bidding bits holding price up a lack of selling equity then price had to reach further than it has
previously to find buyers then it started picking the buyers off now price is moving out and then here
it again deep, reached really deep
and drained this area of buyers and shot through.
It's showing weakness
in the way it's unfolding
from here. Now,
we have weakness in bids. Doesn't mean it's going to sell off.
Still, there's multiple outcome possible.
Still, the most
skewed probabilities, the most
favorable probabilities of a trade,
were just there.
Not here. Not there.
Not there. We're just there.
Yeah.
There's still weakness in bids here.
And it's still very possible.
price breaks down but it's not confirmed we need to see price reflect the weakness and the
bits things like that where it tries to respond tries to form oh shit all right so it tried to respond
had fuck all day had to move to the next number do you get it yeah i want to see if if i'm short here
and i'm looking and i'm seeing bid weakness i want to see whatever bids they are show weakness
fell to move up make multiple attempts and then price moved down i want to see the price
reflect the weakness
and that's the way
I'm going to manage my trade
obviously price
could come all the way back up here
and I still want the high to hold
obviously price couldn't validate my high
you have to test how often
your trade works after the original pickup was invalidated
whether there's any
positive expectancy in that action
are you following me
I'm just trying to give you insight
the amount of detail that's available
just in this shitty little price move here
the amount of extensions that have been filled
the amount of levels that price has responded
of the different variations of levels
here's a watch level here's the shelf retest
b a sorry shelf retest of this inside this
watched apex these are all residual levels
price has had extremely inefficient moves
and then some less inefficient moves
just try to think about what the significance of all this is
I am now connected with price
throughout the duration of us tracking it
I've basically been right about the direction
which you want to get it
I knew it was weak here
I knew all that shit
You knew the level to the left was washed
everything
All that stuff
I'm aware
I'm extracting all the available information
And you are observing
And this mess that I'm making
Is basically stupid
I shouldn't make too too much mess
But that would have been a good trade
To take by the end of the day
It's entirely possible yeah
that price just gets sucked right back in here
you're tracking be intense of it
track it closely
use your timeframes all information
needs to be extracted
all levels need to be defined
and given the location basically to categorize them
every type of price response you need to give it a categorization
how do the price move into it how do price respond
all your shelves when you're tracking prices
all the fractal price runs where the price run fits in
so what is this location in price right now
You can't see it on the one minute and need to have a view of it on the 15 minute. Okay, now we'll get some context
Possible Apex, possible shelf flip, highly inefficient. Did you get it? Yeah, yeah. Now we know the location. I know that this is hitting
technically residual bi-liquity. Some, let's say more savvy information would be this forms the daily shelf or the H-4 shelf. And it wouldn't be too much of a surprise to have thick concentrated bi-liquity.
throughout all of this area of the higher time frame shelf
because we're in a higher time frame price run
which is unusual
it's not a normal dynamic
right so it wouldn't be too much of a surprise
if residual levels bounced
if price bounced off a residual level
that continues to new highs
it's exactly what happens in higher time price runs
by liquidity turns up at these big inventories
it holds price up and by liquidity moves higher and higher
so the fractal runs the building blocks
look as if to get and bid up of residual
levels but the question is always the answer is always there this residual this fractal price
run is located in a higher time frame bullish midflow midflow midflow means imbalance higher time frame
will likely has more liquidity there higher time frame bullish midflow means these inventories
are packing a big punch you get it yeah this inventory here is packing a big punch when price
There's a thick, thick concentration of bi-liquity there.
When price draws back down on this fractal H-1 price run,
it could quite easily find bi-liquity there and get bid up,
because that's exactly what all mid-flow does.
In every single mid-flow, liquidity is accepting higher and higher prices.
Are you following me?
It's the exact same as, like, look, you have this mid-floor.
We have then also inside of it, this fractal price run.
That fractal price run definitely broke shelf there.
and then got bid up off the middle of you know why did they get mid up here is because of the type of the environment that price is in we're seeing bi liquidity except higher and higher prices so it creates in it creates these fractal runs which are getting bit up off the middle of the residual levels bi liquidity is turning up at residual levels in how mad that is bi liquidity is turning up at residual levels or fractal price runs which should be weak which should be weak which should be weak in
indicative of greater imbalance, higher time frame imbalance,
and the significance of high time frame imbalances
for a broader period of time, for a longer period of time,
we consistently see directional volume.
It creates a specific environment
that we have to trade and respond to in appropriate ways.
You follow me?
So hopefully things are making more sense.
I'm going to leave it at that.
We had an apex retest just there.
if you were short it would a shit scared you but that's the way things are
yeah it didn't break through the shelf first did it
or did it no the shop held the price went up
apex retest it could easily break down it could easily run through
yeah so some of them something I want you to take away from this
is how I'm talking about where the price run fits in the high time from context
and the significance of a higher time frame inefficiencies
they are unusual we do not typically have environments
we do not have
we typically don't have environments
where for sustained periods of time
buyers are building positions
time and time and time yet
now this was a highly efficient
daily abolishment flow
so it's not too difficult
you get it
it's about the times when price starts doing this
it becomes a high time frame and efficient
the buying is more aggressive
the buy liquidity is moving higher more aggressively
there's less sell liquidity in the way to avoid
getting clipped people don't want to take on short positions and this goes on day after day after
day the internal structures of this see fractal runs get bit up of residual levels which is quite
frustrating because normally in this environment you see price break a fractal shelf you you typically
get bigger fills yeah where here you see in very minus small fills are you understanding the significance
what I'm saying.
Yeah, yeah.
Like, this environment is shit, bro, but it's real.
It exists.
And this is similar to what we're doing.
What's happening now?
This is what I'm talking about with so much, like, take the information involved, do the work.
Trust me, you know, like, if you track it, even a tenth of the way we just tried to do it there.
Yeah.
You will, we will go into this process of, like, learning for yourself.
Basically, it'll be, it'll be, and fulfill your desire, like, your desire to learn more about more.
it starts fulfilling it that then breeds like motivation then from that motivation you
continue to observe price because you're getting loads of like favorable or or loads of
experience from it so you just simply tracking prices and developing this way becomes much
much more beneficial for your progress curve than I can be yeah what I'm saying is you
will learn more from tracking price than you have than anything you've ever learned from me
and so tracking
your
but trust me
have a shit on the toilet
track it
wake up in the middle of the night
on the bus
track it
in traffic
uh yeah
anyway but I'm
leave you alone
is there any questions
you have
um so
you don't really expect me
to go on to like
the tick charts
and stuff doing
you know the
try it
try it okay
there's no difference
to tick charts
they're just faster
you see how I didn't
you see how I was quite flustered
when I was doing it
it's because of how fast it was not talking
that's natural
but it's fine like you have to remember
yeah
if price responds off this level like it just did
you were not trying to anticipate
the response
you all you had to do is you want to go and observe that level
yeah what happens
you get it yeah
soon you're going to be
I'll say you were tasked to anticipate what's going to happen next
but simply I just want you to get used to tracking price
yeah that's cool then
so what did this respond off go analyze it
draw the level on draw all these levels on before it happens and then if price ends up rolling over
them you're not wrong about anything it just became inefficient yeah that's the risk of it
when it breaks a shelf that becomes inefficient you follow me yeah that's perfect well so yeah
get used to it don't don't don't step back from things that are intense or that you feel you can't
do that's literally that's where you're going to learn yeah all right okay cool